anu.edu.au 2019-06-13

# Privacy - ANU

When you look at The Australian National University (ANU) web site our server makes a record of your visit and logs the following information:

  * your browser's internet address
  * the date and time of your visit to the site
  * the pages you accessed and documents downloaded
  * the previous site visited
  * the type of browser you are using
  * the username entered if accessing a restricted site.

ANU uses this information for statistical purposes and for system administration tasks to maintain this service. We do not attempt to identify individuals of our regular business practices however in the unlikely event of an investigation, the University, a law enforcement agency or other government agency may exercise its legal authority to inspect our server's logs.

The ANU website also uses cookies. These cookies collect information about how and when people use the site, which site was visited immediately beforehand, the types of devices and browsers people are using to visit the website, and visitors' IP addresses. ANU uses the data collected using cookies to better understand our website visitors, and identify how we can improve the web experiences and interactions that we offer. We also use cookies to inform and optimise our advertising by retargeting visitors after they leave the ANU website. We do not use cookies to collect personal information.

If at any stage you provide us with your email address either as part of a message or by completing a web form, we will only use the contact information you provide in accordance with our privacy policy.

External sites that are linked to or from the University site are generally not under our control or responsibility and you are advised to review their privacy statement.

ANU is an 'agency' for the purposes of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and as such complies with the obligations of the Privacy Act within that meaning.

## Disclosure statement

  1. The Australian National University (ANU) is a world-leading university in Australia's capital Canberra which is situated in the Australian Capital Territory. The ANU website is located at: [http://www.anu.edu.au/](https://www.anu.edu.au/). You can reach us on +61 2 6125 5111.

  2. ANU recognises that your privacy is very important to you. As an 'agency' within the meaning of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), ANU complies with the obligations of the Privacy Act including the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) which govern the way we collect, use, disclose, secure and dispose of your personal information.  A copy of the APP's may be obtained from the website of the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner at [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/).

  3. ANU will use the information you submit to better understand your studying preferences and needs. We may also use the information you provide us to update your contact profile and to personalise marketing messages.

  4. The information collected may be disclosed to University contracted service providers which the University uses to perform services on its behalf (such as information technology providers, market research firms, mailing houses and logistics).

  5. ANU will not disclose your personal information to anybody else, including overseas recipients, unless we are required to do so by law - for example, if the information is needed in an emergency or for law enforcement purposes.

  6. The [ANU Privacy Policy](https://policies.anu.edu.au/ppl/document/ANUP_010007) outlines the personal information handling practices of ANU. You have a right to access personal information that ANU holds about you, subject to any exceptions in the Privacy Act.

If you wish to seek access to your personal information or inquire about the handling of your personal information, or make a complaint about how we have handled your information, please contact the ANU Privacy Officer by email at [privacy@anu.edu.au](mailto:privacy@anu.edu.au).
